We're back!
Let's put our stuff down
and go report to the chief.
Yes. There's so much
we have to tell everyone.
Good.
They're growing well.
Dolan!
Good morning, Celina.
The People Saying Goodbye
All dragons trace their origins
back to a single dragon.
He was the progenitor dragon,
and his long life began when
the world came into existence.
Eventually, the gods came to be,
and as they alternated between
discord and reconciliation...
The progenitor dragon came to
realize that he was all alone.
Envious of the gods, he split his
body apart and created new dragons.
From his tail, Hyperion the Destroyer.
From his wings, Vritra the Swift.
From his eyes,
Jormungand the All-Seeing.
From his fangs, Alexander the Piercer.
From his limbs, Leviathan the Eternal.
From his head, Bahamut the Free.
And...
From his heart and soul, which continued
to beat even after he tore himself apart,
one dragon that ruled
over them all was born.
That would be me, in my past life.
So cool...
We'll continue this tomorrow.
I like Bahamut!
Alexander for me!
Are you the resident
storyteller for the kids?
At first, I was only telling my
little brother these stories,
but now, all the kids in the
village come to listen.
That was great.
It sounded almost like you've seen
the dragons with your own eyes.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Things are really looking
up in this village.
All because the residents of the
Forest of Ente have started to visit.
We're all thankful to you for giving
this opportunity to mingle and trade.
And you're our heroes for taking
out those Four Demonic Knights.
I don't blame the forest dwellers
for wanting to come see you.
Could you shake my hand?
Mm, sure thing.
You're Christina, aren't you?
Sorry, she's talking to us right now.
Heh. You were the personification
of grace in combat,
but look at you now. How cute.
Are you making fun of me, Diadora?
Whoa. You can stop teasing Chris now.
Yeah?
I know you're a powerful lamia,
but can you resist the
scent of my black roses?
You smell amazing, Diadora.
What... exactly are you doing?
Dolan, can we go hunting
with Balan after this?
Miu asked me to just before.
Sure. But if you're going,
I'm not exactly needed, am I?
What?!
Oh.
You just drank that milk, didn't you?
I did.
Wait...
Exactly. Miu gave us that milk.
You got paid for the job in advance!
Well, I suppose you'll have to go.
Very well. I'll go with you.
Yay!
I'll have to be wary of the
things you bring in the future.
Don't be like that!
Dolan.
There's a den of armored bears up ahead.
Huh?
I'll engage first! Jalaam!
Now! Get 'em!
What are you doing?
These monsters haven't attacked anyone!
They've only just made it back home
with the forest at peace now!
Don't be stupid!
Wherever they may live,
monsters are a threat to people.
What if that monster kills
someone in the village?
How would you explain that to their family?!
Keep going.
This is such meaningless killing...
Dolan.
No need to overthink it.
They're harmful beasts, unlike me.
Celina?
Dolan!
Why are you checking on the fields?
Why, you ask?
I always check on the fields, don't I?
Yeah, but...
Why would you tend to these fields when
we're abandoning the village anyway?
Huh? We're doing what?
Oh, right. You wouldn't know
since you were away so long.
What are you talking about?
Old Maguru made the decision.
What? But where will we go
in these frontier lands?
Dunno, but it seems we'll all be on our
own when it comes to finding new homes.
That's ridiculous!
There's no way that will work!
Don't get so heated.
The villagers have all come
to terms with it already.
I hear Maguru and Balan are holding a
meeting tonight to give us a rundown.
This makes no sense!
Why are we abandoning this village?!
What's wrong? You look pale as a ghost.
Are you serious about
abandoning Verun Village?!
The decision has been made.
And I'm saying that the
decision makes no sense!
There's no guarantee that everyone
here will find new homes.
We might all be separated!
Are you okay with that?
All our years spent here have
given us knowledge, experience,
and most importantly, bonds to call our own!
We must not abandon these lands!
We cannot hope for further prosperity here.
And that is unacceptable.
I thought you all loved the village!
Perhaps you saw it that way, Dolan.
But we see things differently than you do.
What does she mean?
Was I the only one who loved this village?
Are you leaving already?
Yeah. We have a baby and all,
so the sooner the better.
Good bye, Dolan. Thanks for everything.
Farewell.
Is that the first grimoire I let you read?
Yes.
You can have it if you like.
I have no need for it anymore.
What will you do with it?
This book is very dear and memorable to me.
Why are you staying back
in the village, anyway?
I don't want to let this place die.
Even after it's empty?
You really are a strange one.
Big Bro!
We're leaving today, too.
Oh...
Are you really not coming with us?
I've decided to stay here,
and there's no changing that.
I suppose I've cooked my
last meal for you, then.
Please write to me when you've
settled down in your new home.
I'll come visit.
You say that, but we know you don't mean it.
Of course I do.
You're special, after all.
You'll be fine on your own.
You're sticking to your guns even
after everyone else moved out, huh?
Chris?
You're the only one still unable
to let go. It's pathetic.
Why are you talking to me that way?
Dolan!
You seem tired.
I just made some soup.
I was about to take it to you.
Will you have some?
I will, thank you.
I used Miu's milk for it.
It's probably not as good
as what you made for me,
but I hope it will make you feel better.
Thank you.
That's the last of Miu's milk.
Oh... I'm going to miss it.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
By the way...
Your shelves look awfully empty.
Dolan, the thing is...
Is that...
your home?!
Chris!
You're not safe there!
I'll be fine.
I'm just watching the place burn.
Don't tell me...
Did you set fire to my home?
Yes, I did. And everyone helped.
You're only attached to this
place because you have a home.
So I made it go away.
Home or no home,
I'm not leaving this village!
Oh, that's right.
These fields are important to you, too.
Don't!
What's gotten into you?!
These fields won't be needed
once you leave the village.
Chris...
Celina, help me talk sense into her!
I'm sorry, Dolan.
Huh?
No way...
Yeah, I'm leaving the village, too.
Thank you for everything.
Why? We fought so hard so
that you could live here!
And together, we can deal with
any monsters that appear!
Yes, but...
Please, stay here with me!
Enough of your pathetic wailing.
Get it through your thick skull.
Nobody wants to live with you.
Your little human act has too many cracks.
Everyone knows what you are.
No...
You must be aware of the negative effects
that contact with a being like
you can have on people's lives.
Why?
Where did I go wrong?
For sixteen years, I thought I'd
done my best to help the village.
And yet, the rift had grown so
wide without my realizing it?
"Help" them?
Awfully condescending, aren't we?
Who do you think you are?
All I did was show my family
and fellow villagers my love.
Well, that love was one-sided and lopsided.
You were merely caressing your ego.
You may want to live life as a human,
but did you stop to think that the
humans may not be so accepting of you?
That can't be.
I know the truth.
You used your friend to say
good bye to your past life.
Your feelings have always been
one-sided, and always will be.
Aw, you poor thing.
You will forever be all alone.
Is this the volcano I used to live in?
It's gone.
The wound the hero gave me is gone, too?
Was it all... just a dream?
Was my human life of
sixteen years all a dream?
Are the people I loved no longer beside me?
That's right. It was all a dream.
No, no...
You're no human.
You're meant to be the protector
of all mankind, all life.
That is your job, and it is who you are.
It can't be. I...
I just wanted to be human.
It's time to go back to who you really are.
No...
Wow, that's one big dragon.
Huh?
This is my first time seeing a dragon,
but for some reason,
I feel like it resembles Dolan.
This really must be a dream.
How did you get in here?
Wait, stop right there!
Celina?
That tone of voice... I knew it!
Dragon... You really are Dolan.
Celina? How are you here?
Hm... I went to sleep hoping to see
you first thing in the morning,
and for some reason I was here.
You know who I am?
Of course I do.
You're Dolan of Verun Village,
and when we first met,
we appeased an earth elemental together.
Then we had soup and came up with
a plan so I could live in Verun.
Verun Village welcomed me with
warmth and love, thanks to you.
Whenever I was afraid, you were
there to give me strength.
Whenever I was in danger,
you and Chris protected me.
Then we went to the elven village
and met Gio and the other villagers.
We defeated those strong demons and
had a wild adventure together.
You are the strong and kind,
yet so very fragile,
Dolan of Verun Village.
Am I right?
Dolan, over here.
One, two... and there!
You're so big, Dolan!
C-Celina? I hope you didn't fall off.
You're right here.
You found me when I was all by my lonesome.
Thank you for coming into my life.
I should be the one thanking you, Celina.
You're not safe up there. Come over here.
Wh-What did I just do?!
Gah! I didn't say anything weird, did I?
I couldn't say. I heard it all, though.
You're mean in all the same ways, too.
That's weird. I'm starting to feel sleepy,
even though I'm already dreaming.
Don't worry.
When you wake up, it will be morning.
Right. I'll go see you
tomorrow morning, then.
Good night until then, Dolan.
Good night.
Now, sorry I kept you waiting.
No fair, Celina.
She turned everything upside down.
Yes. I'm proud to call her my friend.
So, what do you want?
You can't call this a friendly
visit to an old friend,
the world's most prominent fallen deity,
the goddess of destruction and
oblivion and my greatest foe,
Al la Kalavith.
If you've shown me this nightmare,
are you once again...
Exactly. Glad you're quick on the uptake.
I've come all the way to kill you, Dolly.
Next Episode
This week's lucky item is grimoire!
Look forward to next time!